# Michael Hageali

1895 S. Morrison Ln. Gilbert, Arizona (480)457-9981 zmanphx2000@yahoo.com

## **Summary**

Motivated, analytical software developer /programmer. Experienced custom programming in .NET Visual Studio, C#, VB, Java, Java Script HTML with SQL databases, WEB API, Ajax, Jquery and Bootstrap, Node js, NPM, MVC, React, MongoDB, RESTful API. I have worked in Healthcare Industry on software development side primarily with HL7 (EDI), database projects. Open to any new position utilizing my experience and skill set. Willing to relocate if needed.

### **Professional Skills**

- C#, VB, Java, HTML, Java Script, .Net programming Visual Studio, CSS, Bootstrap
- SQL Database, T-SQL, MySQL, Stored Procedures scripting, Node Js, MVC, REST API
- HL7 (EDI) development
- TCP/IP Communications
- SQL Data extraction and integration
- Visual Studio Team Management Source Control
- QA testing and planning
- Software design and logic flow
- Technical Solutions Requirements Analysis
- TFS, Git hub source control

# **Experience**

Full Stack Web Development University of Arizona Certification

February - July 2019 - Gilbert, AZ;

Full Stack training 6 -month program.

- Built almost 2 dozen web applications utilizing: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, React.
- Developed websites using **REST API** and **MVC** frame work.
- Deployed on Git Hub and Heroku cloud.

Git Repository: https://github.com/zmanphx

Portfolio: https://zmanphx.github.io/portfolio2/

### **LVM Systems**

Data Team Integrator

Mesa, Arizona

February 2015 – October 2018

- Developed middleware solutions in .NET environment for patient and doctor data
- Project source control using Team Foundation Server (TFS)
- Wrote C# modules for data migration to SQL database.
- Trouble shooting and client support for SQL data exception issues.
- Trained junior level employees with code review and debugging.
- Wrote technical documentation for client enterprise systems.
- Create service estimates of project customization and scoping of billable work.
- Deployed enterprise level modules to multiple SQL server environments for hospitals
- Write and deployed SQL Stored Procedures to automate patient integration process.
- Work closely with business groups and development team to ensure technical design satisfy the business needs.
- Supported the implementation of architecture, tools, processes to facilitate development
- Conferred with users, and team members to develop, understand and update requirements
- Conducted application software testing, prototyping review, integration development for product release.

#### McKesson Health

Client Support Engineer / Developer Analyst Scottsdale, Arizona

June 2001 – February 2015

- Provided analysis for technical solution based on hospital client requirements
- Executed programming updates for application version releases
- Established product road maps and schedules with input from business groups
- Customized C# development, installation, and support of hospital site interfaces.
- Coded HL7 EDI process using hospital vendors: **Epic, Cerner, Star, Touchworks, All Scripts**
- Wrote custom stored procedures Microsoft **SQL database**.
- Project management for data integration for hospital sites.
- Provided data and process analysis for patient data solutions.
- Provided consultative services on technical issues to clients and internal project teams. Installations.
- Provided training for operations personal on their support of deployed applications.
- Coded TCP/IP and HL7 protocols.
- Troubleshooted technical and data issues

#### **Schaller Anderson (Medicare Billing)**

Report Writer, developer

October 1999 – June 2001

• Key Responsibilities: Custom report writing in Crystal Reports to report medical billing statistics.

- SQL database programming
- Created Disease Management statistical reporting

#### **World Com Wireless**

Contractor programmer

January 1998 – October 1999

- Program database logic for wireless billing for monthly promotions.
- Import wireless record plans using custom coding.

#### MicroAge

Catalog developer

August 1995 – December 1997

- Custom developer of CD-ROM product catalog for computer hardware for VAR vendors.
- Produce monthly catalogs with updated pricing.
- Code pricing algorithm key for each VAR vendor

## **Education**

### **University of Arizona**

Full Stack Development -Certification Program 2019 Certification

Training with tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Ajax, web api, Postman, Firebase, Node.js, NPM, Ajax. Web API, RESTful API, MVC, MySQL

## **Brigham Young University**

Bachelor's Degree, Information technology, database design

Business degree with emphasis on information technology and System Development Life Cycle and coding development.